( MUFFLED GRUNT )
( FOOTSTEPS RUNNING )
( OBJECTS CLACKING )
( FAINT CREAKING )
( YELLS )
( BOTH LAUGHING )
( ROARS ) Think you could hide from me , did you ?
Did you read what it said ? It said , " Found you ! "
- It means I tickle ... - ESTHER : Samuel . Bee .
That 's enough .
You don 't want to get overheated .
- I 'm not . - You sure ?
- Good . Because now it 's my turn ! ( LAUGHS ) - ( SHRIEKS )
BEE : Dad , help !
You need help ? Oh , sure , I can help tickle you .
- ( ROARS ) - ( ALL LAUGHING )
I think the bottom of these feet might be very ticklish .
- ( YAWNING ) - Time for bed , Bee .
Thank you .
Mmm ...
Love you , Mommy .
Love you more .
Mommy ?
- ( SOFTLY ) Just for a little while . - ( CLICKS )
Thanks .
( " YOU ARE MY SUNSHINE " PLAYING ON GRAMOPHONE )
MAN : ( SINGING ) You are my sunshine , my only sunshine
You make me happy when skies are gray
( BELL TOLLING )
( DOOR OPENS )
( INDISTINCT CHATTER )
- BEE : Mommy ? - ESTHER : Mmm-hmm ?
Can we play dollies when we get home ?
Well , I think if you help me with the washing up ,
I could play dollies with you all afternoon .
- VICTOR : Sam ! - Yes ! ( CHUCKLES )
VICTOR : Sam !
Morning , Sam .
- Morning , Esther . - Morning .
- Hey , there , busy Bee . - ( BOTH CHUCKLE )
Sam , just wondering if you got that order of mine ready yet .
I got customers coming into my store every day , asking about your dolls .
You can send your son over tomorrow , Vic . They 're ready .
VICTOR : Well , hallelujah .
I guess prayers do get answered , don 't they ?
They do .
All right , well , thank you so much .
Y 'all have a good Sunday .
- You have a good day , too . - You have a lovely day .
In you get .
( CLANGS )
SAMUEL : Damn it ! ( GRUNTS )
Language .
( SIGHS LOUDLY )
There 's a car coming . Why don 't I wave it down and see if we can get some help ?
No , no , no . I got it .
( GRUNTS )
( BOLT CLATTERS )
I 'll get it !
ESTHER : No !
( ESTHER SCREAMS )
B-L-U-E .
Okay , pick a number .
Linda ?
Um ...
- Four . - Okay .
" You will soon make new friends . "
Do mine now .
What 's wrong ?
I just wish you and me were going to a new home instead of a new orphanage .
Sweet Sue does , too .
( JANICE SIGHS )
It 'd be nice to have a home .
Yeah , but only if you 're there .
I don 't wanna go anywhere you 're not .
So let 's swear .
If someone wants one of us , they get both of us .
Okay . I swear .
Good .
Me , too .
You know what I like most about Sweet Sue ?
What ?
She looks just like you .
So how much further is it , Father ?
Jesus , Mary , and Joseph , you 're worse than the children , Sister .
( SCOFFS )
The Mullins agreeing to take us in was a gift from God .
Yeah .
What kind of person isn 't excited about getting a gift ?
I should mention , don 't be alarmed if you don 't see much of Mrs. Mullins at first .
She has a condition , you see .
She was in an accident years ago .
You girls would do well to help her if need be .
( GIRLS MUTTERING )
LINDA : It 's big .
CHARLOTTE : Janice ,
you need help ?
No , thanks . I can manage .
Sister .
She 's one of the unfortunate ones with that polio outbreak ,
but she 's getting stronger every day .
She won 't be a burden . I promise you .
Mmm-hmm .
Mr. Mullins , why don 't you show the girls around ?
I can unload their belongings .
I 'll start inside .
Thank you , Father .
Whoa ! This is as big as a castle .
Which obviously makes us the princesses .
If this is our new orphanage , I think I 'm just fine with never being adopted .
There 's a TV .
The television no longer works . The radio , however , does .
This goes on forever .
You 're right . We 're gonna need a map to find our way around .
Girls , this way .
As you can see , the dining room is more than adequate to accommodate all of us .
- NANCY : Look in here . - CHARLOTTE : Let 's stay together .
Mrs. Mullins and I stay in here .
Feel free to use the rest of the downstairs as you see fit .
Your rooms are upstairs .
CHARLOTTE : Mr. Mullins , is there some way Janice and I could maybe stay down here ?
Me , too .
I 'll be fine .
( SIGHS QUIETLY )
( CLICKS )
( WHIRRING )
I installed it years ago for my wife .
Hasn 't been used in ages .
But it works fine .
Try it , Jan.
If you don 't , I will .
Up is up . Down is down .
But it won 't work
unless you click the seat belt in ,
like this .
Simple .
( WHIRRING )
( CHUCKLES )
Thank you .
( METAL SQUEAKING )
( FAINT RATTLING )
NANCY : I got dibs on next !
Wow , nice .
I guess this is ours .
Let 's take that side .
Kate and Tierney can have these .
What about Linda and me ?
Relax , Janice . This is a big house . There are other bedrooms .
Why can 't Linda and me have those beds over there ?
Okay . But then where would Kate and Tierney sleep ?
BOTH : Wow .
This is neat .
( GIRLS TALKING INDISTINCTLY )
( GASPS )
Locked ,
and it stays that way , too .
Hey , Jan.
In here .
Hey ,
wanna be bunkmates ?
( CHUCKLES )
( PAGES RUSTLING )
- ( LOUD THUD ) - ( GASPS )
- Hey , Sister Charlotte , can we ... - Oh , Lord , ( CHUCKLES )
please bless Nancy with the wisdom to not give people near heart attacks .
Sorry .
What is your emergency ?
Can we go exploring ?
Help Father Massey with your things first , and then ...
- But Mr. Mullins is doing that . - But that doesn 't mean you 're ...
You know how Father Massey is . We don 't wanna get in the way .
- Fine . - She said , " Okay " !
But look out for one another !
( GIRLS GIGGLING )
You coming , Jan ?
Maybe in a little while .
Well ,
maybe I 'll stay , too .
Because you feel sorry for me ?
Well ...
You promised you wouldn 't treat me any differently .
Okay .
- See you ! - ( CHUCKLES SOFTLY )
( FOOTSTEPS RECEDING )
( DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES )
( SIGHS )
( HINGES CREAKING )
( SIGHS HEAVILY )
- ( GASPS ) - ( HINGES CREAKING )
( CLATTERS )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
Dear Lord , thank you for bringing us all together .
- Bless this food for our use ... - ( BELL RINGS )
- And us to thy service . - ( BELL RINGS )
Fill our hearts with grateful praise ,
and help us give you glory each day through .
Jesus Christ , our Lord . Amen .
CHARLOTTE AND GIRLS : Amen .
( EXHALES )
( BELLS RINGS )
If you 'll excuse me .
Carol .
Keep to your own business .
( LIGHTS BUZZING )
And if I die before I wake , I pray the Lord my soul to take .
Please , God , help Linda and me find a good home that keeps us together ...
So we can finally be real sisters ...
With good , loving parents ...
- That hate homework as much as we do . - ( CHUCKLES )
But even if they don 't , that 's okay , too .
- ( CHUCKLES SOFTLY ) - BOTH : Amen .
( SIGHS HEAVILY )
( FOOTSTEPS )
( MOUTHING ) " Find me " ?
( DOOR UNLOCKS )
Nancy ?
Carol ?
Are you guys in here ?
( SHUDDERS )
Forgive me , Father ,
for I am about to sin .
( CHUCKLES )
( FLOORBOARD CREAKS )
( FAINT CLATTERING )
( SIGHS )
( GRUNTS SOFTLY )
( DOOR OPENS )
( HINGES CREAKING )
( LOCK CLICKS )
( FAINT THUD )
( GRUNTING SOFTLY )
( GASPS QUIETLY )
( GASPS , WHIMPERS )
( PANTING )
( DOOR CLOSES )
( FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING )
( SWITCH CLICKS )
( EXHALES )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
CAROL : I heard this is where Mr. Mullins keeps his wife .
- KATE : Does she really wear a mask ? - CAROL : Yeah , she looked like a doll .
NANCY : Mrs. Mullins , you down there ?
- LINDA : Stop it . - ( GIRLS LAUGH )
I think he seems nice .
Why don 't you go find Janice , see what she 's up to ?
Why ?
So you can talk about boys ?
Well , do you wanna talk about boys ?
Gross .
No .
I wanna play a game .
Okay , let 's play hide and seek .
You go hide , and we 'll come look for you .
Okay .
( CHUCKLING SOFTLY )
So are we gonna look for her ?
Maybe .
- ( SNEEZES ) - Bless you .
Thank you .
What are you doing ?
I asked Mr. Mullins if we could use this room for our new classroom ,
and he graciously agreed .
Would you like to help ?
What 's wrong ?
I have a sin to confess .
( SIGHS )
Forgive me , Sister Charlotte , for I have sinned .
- It 's been ... - At least two weeks .
At least two weeks since my last confession .
There 's this room upstairs that we 're not supposed to go into .
But you did anyway .
How 'd you know ?
Because , otherwise , why would you be telling me about it ?
Well , the door was already open .
I don 't know how because Mr. Mullins always keeps it locked .
When I went inside , there was this little doll ,
- and it was really strange in there . - Janice .
Weird things started to happen .
Janice , listen to yourself .
What do I always say ?
A sin is a sin , no matter the context .
More importantly , you absolutely cannot disobey the Mullins .
We only just got here ,
and they 're doing a very generous thing by allowing us to stay with them .
If they decide to no longer have us here ,
we 'll all be split up .
So next time you 're thinking of breaking a rule ,
think of how that could affect the other girls , first .
Do you understand me ?
Yes . I 'm sorry , Sister . I wasn 't thinking .
It 's okay , love .
For your penance , pray one Hail Mary ,
and unpack three of these boxes .
( FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING )
What are you guys doing ?
Unpacking boxes .
Oh .
( BOTH LAUGH )
This place is so creepy .
( GASPS )
( CHUCKLES SOFTLY )
( SOFTLY ) What was that ?
What was that ?
How dare you !
( ALL CHUCKLE )
Oh , Mr. Scarecrow . ( SCOFFS )
( LINDA CHUCKLES )
- ( FAINT CREAKING ) - ( GASPS )
( METALLIC SCRAPING )
( SHRIEKS )
CAROL : Oh .
Found you .
You 're not very good at hiding .
Years of neglect have affected the counterbalance .
There . That should keep the draft down .
Thank you .
( SIGHS ) That was taken in Romania at a convent of cloister nuns .
They have little contact with the outside world ,
but I became very close to these three .
That 's Sister Maria . That 's Sister Anna . And that 's Sister Lucia .
Who 's this ?
I don 't know . I don 't think I even met her .
Is there anything else you need ?
No , thank you .
Good night .
- Ooh , I like him . - ( ALL CHUCKLE )
Which one would you marry ?
Oh , I don 't know .
I guess I 'll just have to date all of them to find out .
( ALL LAUGH )
I just want his eyebrows .
His eyes .
He 's very handsome .
( HUFFS FAINTLY )
( ALL LAUGH )
( GIRLS CHUCKLING )
NANCY : Night time is when Mrs. Mullins gets her powers .
That 's why she 's in bed all day , but at night ,
she can go wherever she wants .
( WHISPERS ) She needs to , so she can feed .
And if you look directly at her , you 'll die .
And to get you to look , she 'll keep saying your name over and over
till you can 't stand it .
( SHUDDERS ) Wait .
Nancy . Nancy .
- Nancy ! - No , Mrs. Mullins . No !
- ( LAUGHS ) - Nancy .
- ( CHUCKLING ) - ( SHUSHES )
( CAROL CONTINUES LAUGHING )
Shh !
( BELL RINGING FAINTLY )
CAROL : Oh ...
No .
She 's ready to feed . ( LAUGHS )
Carol !
- Carol ! - Stop it .
- We 're not supposed to be up . - Well , you were doing it , too .
Me ? ( SCOFFS )
( BOTH LAUGH )
( BELL RINGING )
Okay , why isn 't he answering her ?
- ( FAINT CREAKING ) - ( BELL RINGING )
- ( BELL RINGING ) - ( FLASHLIGHT BUZZING )
- ( BELL RINGING LOUDER ) - ( FLOORBOARD CREAKING )
- ( BELL RINGING ) - ( BOTH SHUDDERING )
- ( WHISPERING ) Nancy . - Don 't look at her .
No ! No , please , please , please !
- Please ! No , please . Please . - ( BELL RINGING )
- Please , God . Please . - Please .
( BELL RINGING LOUDLY )
She 's gone .
She 's gone . She 's gone .
( BOTH SCREAMING )
What 's going on ?
- What on God 's Earth ? - Miss Sister Charlotte !
- Mrs. Mullins ! - She was here .
- We heard her . - In this room .
She was standing right over there .
Who ?
Your wife , apparently .
They said she was just in here .
SAMUEL : Oh , that 's impossible .
My wife hasn 't been able to walk for years .
( BELL RINGING FAINTLY )
CHARLOTTE : Girls .
- Girls ! - ( GIRLS LAUGHING )
Let 's go back to our studies , okay ?
You okay , Nance ?
( CAR DOOR SHUTS )
( ENGINE STARTS )
Did you really see Mrs. Mullins in your room last night ?
Yes . We swear . We were under the covers ...
Nancy , stop it .
We just freaked ourselves out last night . You know that .
( BELL RINGING )
Mrs. Mullins ?
ESTHER : Sister Charlotte ,
could I trouble you for a glass of water ?
Of course .
( MUFFLED CHATTERING )
ESTHER : All of you are more than welcome to stay as long as you need .
It 's good to hear some life again .
We 've been cooped up here so long , I 'd forgotten what that sounded like .
CHARLOTTE : What a lovely picture .
She was taken from us at an early age , unfortunately .
If you could turn away for a moment , Sister ?
Yes , of course .
I 'm very sorry to hear about your daughter .
But we find comfort in knowing she waits for you in Heaven .
ESTHER : I wish that were true .
( FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING )
( " YOU ARE MY SUNSHINE " PLAYING ON GRAMOPHONE )
MAN : ( SINGING ) The other night , dear , as I lay sleeping
I dreamed I held you in my arms
But when I woke , dear , I was mistaken
And I hung my head and cried
You are my sunshine , my only sunshine
- ( CLICKS ) - ( MUSIC STOPS )
LINDA : Oh , my gosh .
( SIGHS )
You shouldn 't be in here .
Well , neither should you .
Whose room is this , anyways ?
The Mullins had a daughter .
It was hers .
" Had " one ?
I think she died .
And I think that was her playing the music , too .
Stop trying to scare me .
I 'm not . It 's the truth .
Then why are we in here ?
- We should leave . - No .
No .
Linda ,
what is it ?
We shouldn 't be in here .
Okay .
I 'll leave in a minute .
Well , I 'm going .
( DOOR SLAMS )
( PUPPETS JINGLING )
( SHUDDERING )
Who 's doing that ?
( SWITCH CLICKS )
( GASPING BREATHES )
( GASPS SOFTLY )
Hi .
( SHUDDERING )
( TAPPING ON GLASS )
You 're the Mullins ' daughter , aren 't you ?
What happened to you ?
BEE : Will you help me ?
What do you need ?
- ( DEMONIC VOICE ) Your soul ! - ( SCREAMING )
( CRYING )
( SCREAMING ) Charlotte !
Sister Charlotte !
( DOORS SLAMMING SHUT )
( WHIMPERING )
( DOOR OPENS )
( CREAKING )
( GROWLING )
( PANTING )
( WHIRRING )
( THUDS )
No ! No !
( WHIMPERING )
( GROWLING )
( SCREAMS )
( WHIRRING STOPS )
( SCREAMING )
( THUDS )
How do you feel ?
Give her some space .
CHARLOTTE : Girls ,
Janice is feeling a little down right now , so we need to do what we can to support her .
Time , I think , is all she needs .
She 'll walk again though , right ?
We 'll have to see .
You need sleep . That 's gonna help you with the healing .
I can 't stay here , Sister Charlotte .
We can 't stay here .
We need to leave .
Leave ?
And go where ?
There isn 't anywhere else for us to go .
I didn 't fall down those stairs .
Something threw me .
What do you mean ?
You always say that ,
even though we can 't see God , we can ...
We can feel his presence .
Well , in this house , I feel a different kind of presence .
What kind ?
An evil one .
It 's coming after me . Coming after my soul .
Your soul ?
Because I 'm the weakest .
No , darling .
Listen , the devil preys on those weak in faith ,
not weak of flesh or bone .
You are as strong as any of us , Janice .
Stronger .
ESTHER : You 're quiet , Samuel .
I think it was a mistake
to bring the girls here .
Why ?
( SIGHS ) The girl ...
The girl that fell .
Maybe she didn 't fall .
Maybe ...
ESTHER : It was an accident .
That 's all it was .
Accidents happen .
It 's been quiet for 12 years .
You should try embracing the presence of the girls
instead of frightening them away .
LINDA : You 'll be better soon .
I don 't think so .
Not this time .
But you have to .
Pretty soon , we 'll find a new home .
( SCOFFS )
No one 's gonna want me now . I 'd just be a burden .
But you swore we 'd stick together .
I take it back .
Maybe I won 't get adopted .
( SIGHS )
You will .
You know why ?
Because you 're special .
You 're gonna get adopted by a nice family somewhere ,
and they 're gonna spoil you so much .
You 're gonna have so many dolls that you won 't even be able to name all of them .
Sure , I can .
- Janice one . - ( LAUGHS )
Janice two , Janice three .
CHARLOTTE : Linda ?
Time for bed .
I wish you 'd come upstairs .
I don 't wanna sleep alone .
Here .
Take Becca .
This way ,
I 'll always be with you .
Then you should have Sweet Sue .
Thank you . ( CHUCKLES )
Remember , before all of this ,
when we used to sneak around the orphanage at night ?
And eat all the chocolate in the pantry ?
Father Massey was convinced that we had mice . ( LAUGHING )
" Oh , Lord . Please cleanse my soul of all my sins ,
- and cleanse our house of these mice ! - These mice ! "
( BOTH GIGGLE )
No matter what happens ,
nothing can erase all of those things we did together .
Night , Linda .
Good night , Janice .
( SIGHS SOFTLY )
( DOOR OPENS )
( INTERMITTENT CREAKING )
( CREAKING CONTINUES )
( LINDA GASPS )
( BALL THUDDING )
( BALL ROLLING )
( TOY GUN CLICKS )
( TOY GUN RATTLING )
( TOY GUN CLATTERS )
( GASPS )
( GULPS )
( FLOORBOARD CREAKING )
( FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING RAPIDLY )
( SCREAMS )
- ( SWITCH CLICKS ) - ( GASPS )
( FOOTSTEPS THUDDING )
( BED RATTLES )
( LINDA SHUDDERS )
( PANTING )
( FAINT GROWLING )
( GASPS )
A little sunlight will do you some good .
I don 't think the sunlight can fix what 's wrong with me .
You mustn 't give up hope .
Hope is a home unto itself .
Dwell in it , and it will protect and keep you .
- What book of the Bible is that from ? - ( BELL RINGS )
The book of Charlotte .
( CHUCKLES SOFTLY )
- But that doesn 't make it any less so . - ( BELL RINGS )
Are you okay here ?
The sunlight actually feels kind of nice .
I told you .
( GIRLS GIGGLING )
KATE : Too low .
( SIGHS )
( DOOR CLOSES )
( THUDS )
( SHUDDERING )
( HINGES CREAK )
( BREATHES HEAVILY )
Sister Charlotte ?
( SCREAMING )
No ! No , no , no !
Stop , please !
( SCREAMS )
- ( GROANS ) - ( CLANKS )
( SHRIEKS )
( BANGING ON DOOR )
( KNOCK )
( FLOORBOARD CREAKING )
- ( FOOTSTEPS THUDDING ) - ( GASPS )
( SHRIEKS )
( SCREAMING )
( GARGLING )
( JANICE SCREAMING )
Janice !
What 's going on ?
JANICE : I couldn 't get out .
Are you okay ?
I 'm fine .
( CHUCKLES SOFTLY )
I 'm worried about Janice .
A few nights ago , she wanted to leave .
Why 'd she wanna leave ?
Probably because this place is off the wall .
She told me the Mullins ' daughter was coming for her .
The Mullins had a daughter ?
She died a long time ago .
- So she 's seeing ghosts ? - ( BELL RINGS )
Keep your voice down .
( SOFTLY ) So she 's seeing ghosts ?
I guess .
Well , you guys saw something .
That wasn 't a ghost . Ghosts can only be of dead people .
But how does that explain what you saw ?
Unless it really was Mrs. Mullins .
Or something was just trying to scare you .
CAROL : You guys are doing a good job of that on your own .
Janice is probably just looking for ways to justify us treating her differently .
I don 't think so .
Of course you don 't .
You 'll know what I mean when you 're older .
Now go . Get to bed .
( FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING )
What are you waiting for ?
Nothing .
You like it ?
It 's nice .
It 's not my finest work .
( EXHALES SHARPLY )
You seem troubled .
Maybe I can help .
I don 't think so .
Talking about the things that bothers us , sometimes ,
it 's all the help we need .
Well ,
it 's Janice .
She 's acting funny .
" Acting funny " ?
She says
she 's seen your daughter .
My daughter
has been dead for a very , very long time .
I know , but , you see ,
Janice went into her bedroom .
She what ?
She knows she wasn 't supposed to , but she found this doll and ...
What doll ?
The one in the white dress .
That 's impossible .
That doll was hidden away .
She mustn 't go near that doll .
Do you understand me ?
( JANICE HUMMING )
( EXHALES SHARPLY )
( JANICE CONTINUES HUMMING )
( HUFFS )
( METALLIC SQUEAKING )
( SAMUEL BREATHES HEAVILY )
Janice , I told you not to use that room .
( SINGING ) Please don 't take my sunshine away
( BONES CRACKING )
( GROWLING )
( STRAINING )
- ( BONES CRACKING ) - ( GRUNTING )
- ( BONES SNAPPING ) - ( SAMUEL GROANING )
( SAMUEL SCREAMING )
Stay here .
Mr. Mullins ?
Mr. Mullins , are you okay ?
( GASPS )
( ENGINE STARTING )
Go get ready for bed , girls . I need to speak to Mrs. Mullins .
( GULPS )
( FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING )
( FOOTSTEPS STOP )
( FOOTSTEPS THUDDING )
- ( GASPS ) - ( FOOTSTEPS STOP )
( PANTING )
( GRUNTING )
Linda , what are you doing ?
This doll , it 's hurting Janice , and it killed Mr. Mullins .
I 'm getting rid of it !
Linda , let 's go back .
( INDISTINCT WHISPERING )
Linda ?
( SCREAMS )
LINDA : No ! No !
( LINDA SCREAMING )
( GRUNTING )
( CRYING )
( BOTH PANTING )
( THUDDING )
- What is that ? - Who cares ? Run !
( POUNDING )
Janice . Janice , I got rid of it .
I got rid of the doll .
( SCREAMS )
CHARLOTTE : Janice ?
Janice ?
- CAROL : What 's going on ? - Where 's Janice ?
- I don 't know . - Go find her .
Hurry !
- What 's going on ? - ESTHER : No !
No ! Get that thing away from me !
It 's back . I knew it was back .
What is it ?
Evil .
The devil itself .
What are you talking about ?
After Samuel and I lost our daughter ,
we prayed and promised our devotion
to whatever power would allow us
to speak or see our beloved girl again .
It started small , the contact .
( " YOU ARE MY SUNSHINE " PLAYING ON GRAMOPHONE )
MAN : ( SINGING ) You are my sunshine , my only sunshine
You make me happy ...
ESTHER : But it was her , our busy Bee .
We knew it was her .
She wanted permission to move into the doll so she could be with us forever .
We said yes , and that 's when it became stronger .
Soon , we could actually see her .
Only in fleeting glimpses , but it was enough .
Our beloved Bee ,
our darling .
Annabelle ?
( BEE GIGGLING )
Even though I couldn 't hold her ,
it was comforting just to have the buzz of activity again .
But we soon realized it wasn 't our Annabelle at all .
( ESTHER GASPS )
( BEE GIGGLING )
( PANTING )
( BEE HUMMING )
( BEE CONTINUES HUMMING )
( BONES CRACKING )
( ESTHER SCREAMS )
Esther ?
( WAILING )
( WHIMPERING )
It was a demonic presence ,
and it was using our Annabelle
to manipulate us into giving it a soul it could inhabit .
It tried to take mine , but Samuel reached out to the Church .
They saved my soul , but the evil was still attached to that doll .
So we locked it away
where it could be surrounded by the word of God .
It was quiet for all these years .
I thought the evil was contained .
We thought helping the girls could be our penance .
But we ended up giving it just what it wanted .
JANICE : ( SINGING ) You are sunshine
My only sunshine
You make me happy when skies are gray
You 'll never know , dear ...
Janice .
Please don 't take my sunshine away
She can walk .
It 's just us , Janice .
Time to cease from sin , Carol .
( GIRLS SCREAM )
- NANCY : Sister Charlotte ! - CAROL : Look !
- It 's Janice . She did this to me . - Look what she did !
- Carol , call for help . - Okay .
And stay together .
( PANTING )
They 're on the way . Let 's get somewhere safe .
( BELL RINGS )
What do we do ?
We can 't just leave her here , can we ?
( BELL RINGS )
CAROL : Mrs. Mullins ?
Mrs. Mullins ?
( ALL SCREAMING )
Girls !
Let 's go . Now !
- ( GIRLS PANTING ) - ( FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING )
Forgive me , Sister , for I have sinned .
( PRAYING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE )
( CONTINUES PRAYING )
- Charlotte ! Charlotte ! - Let 's go !
( GIRLS SCREAMING )
Linda !
( SCREAMS )
LINDA : Go , Kate ! Get help !
Or you could help me .
CAROL : The truck !
NANCY : Come on , come on .
Come in . Close the door ! Close the door !
- Come on ! Go ! - ( ALL PANTING )
- ( ENGINE SPUTTERING ) - ( GASPING )
- No ! - Why ?
- Go ! Go ! - ( ENGINE SPUTTERING )
NANCY : Look .
CAROL : Okay .
- No ! - Hurry !
- I 'm trying ! - It 's there !
( RUSTLING )
( ENGINE SPUTTERING )
- It 's not moving . - I 'm trying ! I 'm trying !
Guys !
( ENGINE STARTS )
Guys ! Guys !
Wait . Wait .
The scarecrow .
- TIERNEY : What scarecrow ? - ( ENGINE DIES )
NANCY : What ?
- ( BANGS ) - ( ALL SCREAM )
- Kate ! - Get out !
( STRAINING )
( BANGING ON DOOR )
- ( STRAINING ) - ( BANGING CONTINUES )
CAROL : The barn ! The barn !
( ALL GASP )
NANCY : Carol .
( PANTING )
What ?
( SCREAMS ) No ! No ! No !
Nancy , I can 't get the door open . Is it locked ?
Can you get it from your side ?
Girls ?
( CRYING ) Nancy ?
( CLANGS )
( CREAKING )
( RUSTLING )
( SHUDDERING )
( BONES CRACKING )
( GROWLING )
- ( GLASS SHATTERS ) - ( WHIMPERS )
( CREAKING )
No .
No . No , no , no !
- ( BELL RINGS FAINTLY ) - ( GASPS )
( SCREAMS )
( GROANS )
( GROWLS )
( SOBBING )
( SCREAMING )
( GROWLING )
( WHIMPERING )
( GASPING )
( BANGING ON DOOR )
Lord , help me .
Lord , help . Help . ( SOBBING )
( SCREAMS )
Carol , it 's me . It 's just me .
Come on .
( BANGING ON DOOR )
JANICE : Linda ?
( DOOR RATTLING )
( GRUNTS )
( CREAKING )
( GASPS )
( SHRIEKING )
( SCREAMS )
( GASPING )
( CREAKING )
( GRUNTING )
No .
( METAL CLANKING )
- Shoot . - ( THUDS )
( LINDA GASPS )
( SCREAMS )
No !
( STRAINING )
( GROWLING )
( GRUNTING )
( PANTING )
Sister Charlotte ?
( RATTLING )
JANICE : You know what I like most about Sweet Sue ?
She looks just like you .
( SOFTLY ) Oh , my ...
( FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING )
- JANICE : Linda ? - ( GASPS )
Where are you , Linda ?
Linda ?
( GASPS )
Come out and play .
Found you !
( SCREAMS )
( GROANS )
You swore that , if I found a home , you 'd come , too .
You know what they say about breaking a swear .
You go straight to hell .
CHARLOTTE : Janice !
Forgive me .
( SCREAMS ) No !
Let me out !
( DEMONIC VOICE ) Let me out !
( GROWLING )
- ( GLASS CLINKING ) - ( BOTH GASPING )
( " YOU ARE MY SUNSHINE " PLAYING DISTORTEDLY )
( RATTLING )
Go !
- CAROL : Sister Charlotte ! - NANCY : Sister Charlotte !
- ( ALL WHIMPERING ) - ( GROWLING )
( HOUSE CREAKING )
- ( GLASS SHATTERING ) - ( ALL SCREAM )
( ALL PANTING )
( SOBBING )
( SIRENS BLARING IN DISTANCE )
Anything ?
I 'm afraid not .
Still no sign of the girl .
But at her age ,
how far could she have gone ?
Don 't worry .
We 'll find her .
The house is blessed .
Whatever evil was here is no longer .
But the doll .
It was a conduit for the evil .
That evil has moved on .
Now the doll is just a doll .
So which one of you gets this ?
How are you holding up ?
I 'm okay .
You know , that wasn 't Janice back there . That was
something else .
I know .
Hi , there .
Welcome . Let 's go right inside , shall we ?
Sure .
She mostly keeps to herself and can be a bit quiet , but she 's a lovely girl .
She 's just been through a lot .
I think you will love her .
Hello . There 's someone here to see you , sweetie .
I wanna introduce you to Mr. and Mrs. Higgins .
MR. HIGGINS : And you must be ...
Annabelle .
MRS. HIGGINS : Annabelle ?
What a lovely name .
We brought you a present .
I hope you like dolls .
( CHUCKLES )
( LAUGHS )
( WOOD CREAKING )
- Did you hear that ? - Yeah .
What is it ?
- You stay here . - No , no , no ! No , wait !
It 's all right . It 's okay . It 's all right , sweetheart .
I 'm just gonna take a quick look . Call the police .
- ( CHOKING ) - ( GASPING )
- MRS. HIGGINS : Annabelle ! - Hi , Mom .
( WHIMPERING )
( SCREAMING )
John ?
( SONG PLAYING )
MAN : ( SINGING ) The other night , dear
As I lay sleeping
I dreamed I held you in my arms
But when I woke , dear , I was mistaken
And I hung my head and cried
You are my sunshine , my only sunshine
You make me happy when skies are gray
You 'll never know , dear , how much I love you
Please don 't take my sunshine away
I 'll always love you and make you happy
If you will only say the same
But if you leave me and love another
You 'll regret it all someday
You are my sunshine , my only sunshine
You make me happy when skies are gray
You 'll never know , dear , how much I love you
Please don 't take my sunshine away
( MUSIC BOX PLAYS )
( DOOR OPENS )
( HINGES CREAKING )